

Personal info:

Date of birth: 1/1/1977Nationality: Sudan

-Marital status: Married

-Gender: male

 -Address: Open University of Sudan-Alfasher

-Phone: +249912950497

• -E-mail:

mahmoud12958@gmail.com

Languages:

- -Arabic Mother tongue
- -English the second Language

Skills:

- HTML,CSS,JavaScript
- Development: Android/IOS software UX and UI, SQL, Xcode,swift,Github.
- Windows, macOS, Linx, Adroid, IOS.
- Data entry
- Problem-solving
- communication skills
- The ability to work under pressure.
- Teamwork.

Habits:

- Blogging
- Learn to play musical instruments

Summary

Mahmoud Ahmed Mahmoud Gadelrab (IT technician)

Insightful Information Technology Manger with 12 years of IT leader ship experience including oversight of infrastructure, application support, security and other guest related services. Dedicated to customer satisfaction with focused delivery of technical solutions. Proven Leader in directing operations, maintenance and support of complex systems. Excellent communicator and influencer in working collaboratively with IT Leader ship teams to define and accomplish project milestone. Highly adept in problem- solving, technology needs assessments, implementation and staff training.

Work experience:

E-learning officer

Open University Of Sudan- North Darfur state branch from January 2017 until now.

Job Description & Responsibilities

- **1**-Providing technical support to University employees in all e-leaning programs.
- **2-** Holding training courses for faculty members and students to deal with e-learning management system and spread the culture of e-learning.
- **3** Updating and develop programs, devices, and networks.
- **4** Providing a control center for electronic exams to avoid technical problems.
- **5** Installing safety and protection programs to ensure the confidentiality of electronic exams.
- **6-** Make sure that students' grades are entered in to the electronic system.

University Registrar

Open University Of Sudan- North Darfur state branch from January 2010 until 2017

. Job Description & Responsibilities

- 1-Register students and schedules on the system and from matching them to what has been paperback.
- 2- Make sure that the study schedules for the next semester are complete and that the lectures will start from the first academic day.
- 3- Communicate with the General Administration of Admission.
- 4- Receiving exam papers from colleges and make sure that the observers who have been appointed are present.
- 5- Supervising through direct coordination with heads of departments on the procedures for receiving the answer paper after the exams to make sure that they are delivered for timely correction.
- 6- Work with the registrars of departments as team work to customise students within the college's specializations.

IT manager:

Open University Of Sudan- North Darfur state branch from January 2005 *until 2010*

. Job Description & Responsibilities

- Network Security
- 1-Boosted productivity by 30% by analyzing departmental needs, identifying pitfalls and aligning it with the business objective.
- 2-Configured and deployed antivirus tools and directed network security initiatives for 250+ remote & end-user.
 - Troubleshooting & Issue Resolution
- 1-Developed innovative network troubleshooting methods to reduce downtime by 20% and lower repair costs by 30%.
- 2-Planned, directed & designed all operational activities of the IT department to enhance mission -critical business operations.
 - Hardware & Software Maintenance
- 1-Reviewed the allocation & adequacy, and service levels.
 - Network Administration

- 1-Created & managed disaster plans and maintained data backup 2-Monitored changing network technology & kept abreast of the latest updates.
 - Technical Support & System Up gradation
- 1-Spearheaded team of 10 employees
- 2-Rendered technical support to 350+ users & installed 30 new printers as a Desktop Support Technician.
- 3-Installed an upgraded 350+ computer systems to the latest versions of Windows 10.

Educational certificates:

Sudan University of Science and Technology – Diploma in computer Science from 2000 to 2003

Professional certificates:

-Maintenance of computer and networks- at (SUDATEL) the Sudanese Telecommunication Company Academy. From 30/1/2006 to 3/5/2006.

Training Courses:

- 1-The E-learning by using moodle package at Open University of Sudan form January 2008.
- 2-Academic web based System at Open University of Sudan form January 2010.
- 3-Advanced training in admission, registration and certification- at Open University of Sudan form April 2013.